Open Menu Close Menu

Open Menu Close Menu

Privacy policy.
---------------

This privacy policy applies between you, the User of this Website and Tiphereth Ltd, the owner and provider of this Website. Tiphereth Ltd takes the privacy of your information very seriously. This privacy policy applies to our use of any and all Data collected by us or provided by you in relation to your use of the Website.

#### Please read this privacy policy carefully.

Your privacy is important to us. It is Tiphereth Ltd’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect from you across our website, https://www.tiphereth.org.uk.

#### Collection of data.

We only ask for personal information when we truly need it to provide a service to you. We collect it by fair and lawful means, with your knowledge and consent. We also let you know why we’re collecting it and how it will be used.

We don’t share any personally identifying information publicly or with third parties, except when required to by law, or where we need to do this for practical purposes.

Here is a list of the times we collect your information:

1. When you make a donation we record your name, address and email address. If you are making a one-off payment we do not store your card details once the payment has been authorised. If you are making a regular donation by Direct Debit then our Direct Debit provider holds your bank information. This data is held on databases hosted by Blackbaud Inc, the owner of JustGiving and our database system).
    
2. When you order firewood or compost we will retain your name and address details in order to make the delivery. Your card details will be processed but not retained by us once the payment is authorised. You will be given the option to join our mailing list to be told when new supplies of wood are available for sale.
    
3. When you join our newsletter mailing list we will record your email address, and sometimes your first and last name. This data is held by Squarespace Inc. wh provide our mailing list service. You may unsubscribe at any time by following the link at the end of each newsletter.
    
4. When you contact us using the contact form on our website we will store your name and email address until we have responded to your enquiry. At the end of our communication with you, we will delete your original enquiry. This deleted data will be held in our backups for thirty days and then deleted.
    
5. When you apply for a job, or a volunteer role with us, we will collect considerable personal information from you. This will normally be sent by you to us by postal mail or email. But for the avoidance of doubt: we only retain your data until the recruitment process is complete. If you are unsuccessful it will be deleted. If successful, it will become part of your personnel file.

#### Data storage

We only retain collected information for as long as necessary to provide you with your requested service. What data we store, we’ll protect within commercially acceptable means to prevent loss and theft, as well as unauthorised access, disclosure, copying, use or modification.

Our website may link to external sites that are not operated by us. Please be aware that we have no control over the content and practices of these sites, and cannot accept responsibility or liability for their respective privacy policies.

#### Where We store your Personal Data

Where we store your personal data in our own systems, it is stored on secure servers located in the UK or the European Economic Area ("EEA") operated by Microsoft Inc.

Some of the data that we collect from you and process using our website may be transferred to and stored at, a destination outside the UK or the European Economic Area ("EEA") by one of our suppliers. Specifically Blackbaud Inc and Squarespace Inc. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing.

In particular, your data may be stored by our website host on servers in the USA as well as in the EU. The USA does not have the same data protection laws as the United Kingdom and EEA. However, a Data Processor Agreement has been signed between Tiphereth Ltd and each of its data processors. These data processor agreements are designed to help safeguard your privacy rights and give you remedies in the unlikely event of a misuse of your personal data.

We will not otherwise transfer your personal data outside of the United Kingdom OR EEA or to any organisation (or subordinate bodies) governed by public international law or which is set up under any agreement between two or more countries.

If you would like further information please [contact us](https://www.tiphereth.org.uk/contact).

#### Cookies

Our website uses cookies to collect data on visitors to our website. This data is only used to determine how the site is being used and does not contain any data that we could use to personally identify you. These cookies are only used within our website and will not track you elsewhere.

#### Limitations

We take appropriate measures to ensure that all personal data is kept secure including security measures to prevent personal data from being accidentally lost, or used or accessed in an unauthorised way. We limit access to your personal data to those who have a genuine business need to know it. Those processing your information will do so only in an authorised manner and are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We also have procedures in place to deal with any suspected data security breach. We will notify you and any applicable regulator of a suspected data security breach where We are legally required to do so.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although We will do our best to protect your personal data, We cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted through any online means, therefore any transmission remains at your own risk.

#### Your right to refuse.

You are free to refuse our request for your personal information, with the understanding that we may be unable to provide you with some of your desired services.

#### Your acceptance of these terms.

Your continued use of our website will be regarded as an acceptance of our practices around privacy and personal information. If you have any questions about how we handle user data and personal information, feel free to contact us.

This policy is effective as of 1 September 2021.

#### Tiphereth

55 Torphin Road  
Edinburgh, EH13 0PQ  
0131 441 2055

Registered Charity SC017483 | VAT Number 439 4154 82

Copyright © 2021 Tiphereth / All rights reserved. [Terms of Service](https://www.tiphereth.org.uk/terms-of-service) / [Privacy Policy](https://www.tiphereth.org.uk/privacy-policy)

**Social Media**
